<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Viktor Rognås</title>
    <link>https://vrognas.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Viktor Rognås</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2020, Viktor Rognås</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vrognas.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Software management with Homebrew 🍺</title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/post/homebrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/post/homebrew/</guid>
      <description>One thing that GNU/Linux users are familiar with is the concept of a “package manager”. A package manager is a tool that keeps track of software for you. It installs it, uninstalls it, upgrades it, etc. On macOS there isn’t any package manager installed by default (perhaps the App Store could be seen as some form of package manager?), so for all you macOS users out there I highly recommend you install Homebrew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat for the command line!</title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/post/cheat-unix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/post/cheat-unix/</guid>
      <description>When you start out using the command line, you will notice that there are many small and handy programs (also referred to as “commands”) you can run. You might start out using pwd (for “print working directory”), which will tell you what directory you are currently in. Then you might use programs such as ls to “list” the contents of a directory, and you might use cd to “change directory” to another directory you might want to go to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My view on estimating kidney function in pharmacometrics</title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/post/my-view-on-estimating-kidney-function-in-pharmacometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/post/my-view-on-estimating-kidney-function-in-pharmacometrics/</guid>
      <description>In pharmacometric practice we often use some formula to estimate kidney function. Most often the Cockcroft-Gault1 (CG) formula is used. Other formulas used include MDRD2 (6- or 4-variable versions) and the CKD-EPI.3
These equations differ in how they were developed, in what population, and what they estimate! Something to keep in mind is that CG estimates creatinine clearance, while the CKD-EPI and MDRD estimate GFR. Both CKD-EPI and MDRD are also adjusted for body surface area4 (BSA), which CG is not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useR!2019</title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/post/user-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/post/user-2019/</guid>
      <description>Bonjour!
So I recently attended the yearly R conference called useR! It was a great experience to attend presentations of the developers of many packages that I have been using. I especially enjoyed hearing Hadley Wickham (tidyverse/dplyr/ggplot2), Lionel Henry (rlang/tidy-eval), Romain François (dplyr), Terry Therneau (survival) and Achim Zeileis (colorspace).
Lionel Henry’s talk got me inspired to learn more about tidy-eval and how it is used to write functions in the tidyverse!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Typesetting</title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/post/math-typesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/post/math-typesetting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Viktor Rognås</title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/about/</guid>
      <description>A personal blog by Viktor Rognås.
I am a PhD student in Pharmacometrics at Uppsala University.
My PhD project is using statistical models to help overcome antibiotic resistance, and is a part of Uppsala Antibiotic Center.
Degrees   Master of Science in Engineering, Uppsala University 2017 Specialization: Chemical Engineering, Pharmaceutical Science
  Bachelor of Science in Technology, Uppsala University 2014 Specialization: Technology, Mathematics
  Diploma  School of Entrepreneurship, Uppsala University 2017</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touch Typing</title>
      <link>https://vrognas.com/post/touch-typing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrognas.com/post/touch-typing/</guid>
      <description>It all started out with me trying to learn Vim I came across the term “touch typing” when I was looking in a book about Vim (the text editor). The book is called Practical Vim: Edit Text at the Speed of Thought, by Drew Neil. In there I read the following in the foreword:
 Learn to Touch Type, Then Learn Vim
If you have to look down to find the keys on the keyboard, the benefits of learning Vim won’t come fast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
